<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 23kmph</title>
    <link>http://www.23kmph.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 23kmph</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 13:32:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.23kmph.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Super Randonneur Title</title>
      <link>http://www.23kmph.com/post/My-First-Super-Randonneur-Title/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 13:32:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.23kmph.com/post/My-First-Super-Randonneur-Title/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It all started when I was setting goals for the year 2016. I wanted to get a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randonneuring#Awards&#34;&gt;Super Randonneur&lt;/a&gt;(SR) title within this year. To get that title one needs to cycle 200, 300, 400 and 600km in one french year. I will talk about my 600km experience as it is the longest ride in SR series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madras Randonneurs(MR) is the official club for conducting &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randonneuring&#34;&gt;brevets&lt;/a&gt; in Chennai. It is a part of Audax Club India which comes under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.audax-club-parisien.com/FR/&#34;&gt;Audax Club Parisien&lt;/a&gt;, France. As usual Madras Randonneurs opened the registrations for 600km brevet ride two weeks before the flag off date. While registering, I was so sceptical about it. I had a month of gap between my previous 400km ride and this upcoming 600km, In that month I rode only 3 short rides due to some tight deadlines at work. I felt whether I have enough practice to go for a 600km?. People said, there is always next time, But the challenge lies in not quitting this time. With all these thoughts in mind, I just registered with a hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week before the flag off, I started planning and creating check lists. I also called few experts who already won many SR titles to get some tips about the route and noted it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed a post in facebook stating that there was a free pre ride stretches session being conducted by a physio therapy clinic for 600km riders. So, two days before the flag off, I went there to meet a physio called Naresh. He welcomed me with a smile and asked me about my preparation for upcoming 600km ride. While in the conversation, I asked him why no people came in for pre ride stretches. He said, some people are afraid about stretching before the ride, I was like, &amp;ldquo;why should riders be afraid of stretches&amp;rdquo; and slowly laid down on the treatment table. After giving foam roll treatment, Naresh tied me to the table with a tight strap. I felt like I am inside a torture chamber and I had second thoughts. He stretched my back, legs and major muscles in it for half an hour. And for that half an hour I literally shouted and cried (this was my first stretches session with an actual physio). Once the stretches were over he also threw me some tips on the 600km route, do&amp;rsquo;s and dont&amp;rsquo;s in the ride. Finally I shook hands with him and left the place saying, &amp;ldquo;Now I know why riders didn&amp;rsquo;t show up for pre ride stretches&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag off was on Friday 7pm, I had to take the day off from my work to get some sleep on Friday morning. I was awake a little late on Thursday night so that I can get more sleep on Friday morning. Unfortunately in that day construction men were hired to fix the roof and terrace of my apartment. Then, I managed to get some sleep along with the thuds and bangs at the top of my head. I woke up at 2pm, had a good lunch with more carbs and did a final check on the bike. It was 4:30pm and I need to ride 12km to the flag off location which is Just Buy Cycles showroom. To avoid traffic, I started at 4:30pm itself and reached the flag off point at 5:15pm. As usual like every other cyclists, when they get to see the accessories in showroom, they buy something for sure. I did the same, Got water bottles, energy gels and chamois cream to keep my stomach and butt healthy during the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1st-control-point-just-buy-cycles-showroom-0km&#34;&gt;1st control point - Just Buy Cycles showroom (0km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 6:30pm and I saw lots of riders getting ready to face the two sleepless nights. After getting the bike check done by organisers, I got the seal in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randonneuring&#34;&gt;brevet card&lt;/a&gt; for 1st control point. Then 3 minutes before the flag off, I took out my phone to start GPS to track my ride, I was shocked to find out that the touch screen stopped responding and I found a crack at the bottom of the screen. Without a phone its difficult to track the ride or refer route and I need to spend more time in unmanned control points. Mostly ATMs are unmanned check points, we need to insert our ATM card and take a receipt with timestamp on it. But If we have a phone, we can save time by taking a selfie in front of the unmanned control point and show it to the organisers in next CP instead of the receipt. Now I cant do any of these, and I cant contact anyone in case of an emergency. Luckily my friend, Balaji Prasad from my cycling group: WCCG who came there to cheer us at flag off gave his spare phone. Even though it was not a smartphone I thanked him and swapped the phones with him, Not to mention that I had been running around the showroom asking for a pin to eject the SIM card from the broken phone. So this is how the conversation went inside JBC :
&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.23kmph.com/images/start_point.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My First Super Randonneur Title images/start_point.jpg&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    
    Sudhakar(left), Myself(right) at start point
    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me : &lt;em&gt;*In hurry&lt;/em&gt;* Do you guys have a pin or needle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Guys at showroom searching for 3 minutes&lt;/em&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me : Can you please make it faster, the ride is about to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store Manager : We don&amp;rsquo;t have one, by the way why you want one now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me : I need to eject my SIM card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Store Manager : &lt;em&gt;*Took his wallet slowly and gave a proper SIM card tray ejector&lt;/em&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me : Sh*t, I should have mentioned a SIM card ejector already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2nd-control-point-i-o-b-atm-87km&#34;&gt;2nd control point - I.O.B ATM (87km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I was able to start my ride in time and joined the peloton with my fellow riders Sudhakar and Prasad. We already created a whatsapp group a week back, discussed about the routes and difficulties to tackle the 600km BRM. Our first vital target was to reach the 1st unmanned control point at 87km. For nearly 20km we had to deal with the city traffic, and I lost the peloton in the traffic. I was searching both of the riders for some 15km, Then when they crossed me I realised I am ahead of them and joined the peloton. We cleared the traffic and hit the outskirts of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Highways was so dark and calm, occasionally high speed vehicles beamed their head lamp on us. Our peloton was so energetic and had a good pace of 30kmph, so we were able to reach the first CP 3+ hours before the cut off time. Right after taking selfie from my fellow riders phone, we left the CP without wasting further time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3rd-control-point-a2b-hotel-186km&#34;&gt;3rd control point - A2B hotel (186km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to keep up with the peloton so that I can show my photo from their phone as a proof for crossing 1st CP and no way I can take a selfie with the emergency phone that I&amp;rsquo;ve got. Next vital target was the manned control point : A2B hotel at 186km. We stopped at two places to have dinner which we carried and some eggs. I used this break to make my butt comfy with chamois cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After putting down the head, pedalling and staring at the tail lamp of the front rider, I realised we were reaching the 2nd CP. We reached the 2nd CP around 4:45am which is approximately 10hrs on saddle so far. At this CP I was able to see the volunteers welcoming us. I saw few riders who came earlier, lying around the grass randomly and few of them enjoying their beer. Without further delay, I got my brevet card signed and sealed. We spent some 15 minutes, stretching our legs and using restrooms. we are just 15km away from hitting 200km mark, we wanted finish 200km within the sun rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4th-control-point-u-turn-sona-meena-hotel-301km&#34;&gt;4th control point(U-turn) - Sona Meena Hotel (301km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So exactly at 200km we found a small tea shop with rope bed put under a tree. It was 6am, Sudhakar and Prasad were enjoying the tea while I was playing with a white puppy named Rosie. She was too cute and after spending time with her I found my mind relieved. All the experts who did many 600km rides in this route advised me that the stretch : 300km(U-turn) to 420km will be toughest stretch with more headwinds and heat. Which means the 100km stretch towards the U-turn should have tail winds. But unfortunately that day It was opposite. The 200km to 300km stretch was full of heavy headwinds which was unexpected and our mind wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for it. We struggled to maintain the peloton, Our speed dropped to 15kmph. Once the sun came up, It was directly showing its fierceness on our face. At 230km we had breakfast at some highway hotel. Then got back into the saddle with the energy to tackle the headwind, Right after some 4km of ride, our peloton broke. One rider was behind me and other zoomed forward. I was unable to spot any of my peloton partners in front or in back. Then, I decided I am on my own to face this head wind, went into drop position and pedalled for an hour. I checked my cyclo-meter and felt bad to see that I covered only 10km in an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be no challenges, if everything goes smoothly by plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put down my head and started to suffer. Took two 5 minute breaks in between to grab some juice. Finally some 10km before the U-turn, I met Sudhakar again. So we tagged up and reached the U-turn control point at 1:45pm, which is around 19hrs of saddle time so far. I saw volunteers cheering up and welcoming us.
&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.23kmph.com/images/u_turn.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My First Super Randonneur Title images/u_turn.jpg&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    
    Sudhakar(left), Myself(middle), Prasad(Right) at U-turn point
    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I parked my bike, got my brevet card signed. I took out my
handlebar bag and gave it to volunteers as it was touching
my front wheels often. It slowed me down when I adjusted
it every time. MR club booked rooms for the riders to
refresh. We went there, changed clothes, had a 10 minute
nap(This was my first sleep in past 18hrs on bike), then
we grabbed lunch and left the CP at 2:35pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5th-control-point-a2b-hotel-415km&#34;&gt;5th control point - A2B Hotel(415km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to dump as much as the essential accessories into my jersey pockets from the handlebar bag that I dropped off at U-turn. Now, I need to ride the rest of 300km with limited supplies and only a small saddlebag on the back.
Since we faced heavy headwinds and took a U-turn, now for next 100km I expected there should not be any headwinds, there weren&amp;rsquo;t, but we faced some cross winds. Our peloton  still maintained a good pace. Again due to a series of bridges and noon&amp;rsquo;s heat the peloton broke. As usual Prasad zoomed off and Sudhakar was behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was confused whether to sprint and catch Prasad or to slow down and wait for Sudhakar. Tried both, but never happened. With 90 more kilometres to go for next CP. I broke down the target into 20km chunks and started hitting it one by one. After doing 70+ km, I met another good peloton, It was none other than my WCCG group guys whom I use to ride with all the time. I joined them and reached the 4th CP around 9:30pm. This time the volunteers had a massager machine. After getting the brevet card signed. I jumped into the massaging session for 10 minutes and had dinner with the new peloton riders at A2B hotel. Since its going to be 2nd night without sleep, our body was carving for a good nap. So we slept for 20 minutes and started from that CP at 10:40pm, Saddle time was 28hrs so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6th-control-point-only-coffee-525km&#34;&gt;6th control point - Only Coffee(525km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As experts said, First Night(pun intended) you will be able to stay active as you are excited but second night your sleep hits you very hard due to tiredness of the previous night ride. With 110km to pedal for next CP, my body was craving for caffeine doses. I was also not in sync with the new peloton as I joined it very recently. Until the group stopped for coffee, I was keeping myself awake by sprinkling water on my eyes from my sipper bottle. When they stopped for coffee, I filled up one of my bottle with coke + salt. After a hot coffee, We again jumped back into saddle with 95km to go for next CP. I was sipping coke to maintain the caffeine in the body, At one point, as usual I took my sipper, splashed it on my face/eyes. When my eyes started burning I found out that I took the wrong bottle with coke and salt in it. I swapped the bottle and washed my eyes with water while on saddle. We had two 10 minutes nap and in second nap I had to stay awake to watch out for vehicles as the other riders took a nap almost in middle of a service road. I alerted few vehicles with my blinker light. Then everyone woke up and was ready to ride, It was 3:00am, approximately 32hrs on bike and still 60km more to go for Only Coffee CP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt sleepy just after 20 minutes in saddle, as in previous nap session I was awake, watching the riders sleeping, I am not sure whether my mind played a game on me. I decided to break the peloton and slowed down. I was alone and It was pitch dark, I started getting random hallucinations. Whatever the junk I saw on the road side in that pitch dark seemed to be like a corpse to my mind. I was alone in that pitch dark, I cant just nap on road side as we use to do while in group. After sometime I found a well lit petrol station. I entered into it, sat on the floor and closed my eyes for 10 minutes. I opened my eyes and checked my cyclo-meter, It was 3:30am and I still got 30km to cover for next CP which closes at 5:55am. So I got back to the saddle and rode that 30km to reach Only Coffee CP at 4:50am. Over there, other riders and volunteers solaced me. The place was well lit and so lively for my eyes that strived the pitch dark a while back. MR club had arranged a super breakfast with hot coffee for all riders. After finishing the breakfast, I took a 40 minute nap (longest sleep time I had in past 35 hours). I woke up and found Sudhakar Raju, My peloton buddy. We greeted ourselves, cheered and got back to saddle along with Prasad at 6:00am. It was 35hrs on saddle so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7th-control-point-just-buy-cycles-601km&#34;&gt;7th control point - Just Buy Cycles(601km):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final target is the last finish point, which is 76km away from us with 5 hours of cut off time. I enjoyed the orange skies of the rising sun. The sun rays took away all my sleeplessness, made me feel refreshed and gave me hope - Rays of hope, may be?. All these positive energy lasted until I got a vomiting sensation. I was searching for some soda to clear it. The more I tried to pedal, the more I felt that I will puke. Then the elevation hit us. It hit us so hard that after 25km we had to stop to grab some eggs and Pepsi. Finally after some soda, with my less vomiting sensation and more energy, now we had 50km to finish and it was 7:15am. As we were nearing the city, the increasing traffic slowed us down a bit. We managed to get through the signals, traffic and finally had 25km for finish line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I was forced to slow down due to some fatigue and traffic, so I left the peloton. I was riding through the city slowly for last 25km. As time passed by, I realised that I was nearing the finish point. Even though my body was tired, my mind felt so happy for my first Super Randonneur title. It was 596km mark and my mind was happily climbing one of the last bridge in Velachery, suddenly my legs said, I need more power to pedal, my mind sent few signals to legs asking why?, Since my legs are not smart enough, they didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to respond to that and asked for more power again. My mind instructed my eyes to take a look down to investigate whats happening, and why the hell my legs demand more power. My eyes looked down, then signalled the mind something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternate-ending&#34;&gt;Alternate ending:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all these happened within a fraction of second, I realised that my rear wheel went flat. In 45 minutes the finish line closes and I had 4km to cover with a flat. Even though I had 6 spare tubes and proper puncture kit to fix it. My hands were too numb to even open my saddle bag. After 2 failed attempts of trying to take stuffs out of my saddle bag. I looked back and forth for any riders to help me, I found none. Just bikes, cars, buses honking and polluting but no cyclists. I saw my college bus crossing around, Given that I did not have a  deep sleep for past 39hrs, I started hallucinating about my old college life, junior girls smiling at me while crossing. Then suddenly a voice came,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;RUN&amp;rdquo;..
I was like, What?&lt;br /&gt;
It said again &amp;ldquo;START RUNNING&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br /&gt;
But am I suppo..&lt;br /&gt;
Again it said, &amp;ldquo;SHUTP AND RUN&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice was from my gut feeling, I listened to it and started running by carrying the cycle on shoulder. After a minute, I realised, Its not necessary to carry the cycle as the wheels can still rotate and I put down the bike and  rolled with it. I ran, walked, ran and walked, finally I again ran and reached the finish line at 10:35am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divagaran, one of the main coordinator of our group WCCG, was standing there, he clapped, cheered and welcomed me. He got my bike from me and parked it. Meanwhile I ran inside and gave my brevet card for final finish line stamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw people, lots of people, families of other riders, cutting cakes, celebrating, welcoming the finishers with garlands. Some people already knew that I came by running as a volunteer saw me and informed them already. Shun - A veteran cyclist gave me ice packs for my palm numbness. Divagaran massaged my palms and my shoulders. I heard like 14 voices saying congrats from different directions in parallel.  At that moment I wished anyone from my family should have been there with me.
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.23kmph.com/images/velocita.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My First Super Randonneur Title images/velocita.jpg&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    
    Meet my bike, velocità
    
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, thats how I got my first Super Randonneur title. And by the way, I am Naren. I reside in Chennai and ride with an awesome group called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/wccgisthebest&#34;&gt;WCCG (We are Chennai Cyclists)&lt;/a&gt;.
I dedicate this SR title to my father. During my childhood he is the one who ran behind me, teaching me how to ride a cycle and I also dedicate this to my group WCCG where I started cycling again and continuously meeting loveable riders and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to thank my physio Naresh from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physionash.com&#34;&gt;Bone and Muscle Advanced Physiotherapy Clinic&lt;/a&gt; who made me cry before the ride by giving me stretches. Its only because of his stretches I got no single injury throughout my 600km ride. Now, He is my personal trainer for my core strengthening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The saddle average speed of my first 600km was 23kmph. Hence the name &lt;a href=&#34;www.23kmph.com&#34;&gt;23kmph.com&lt;/a&gt;. I will write more about my previous/upcoming cycling, travelling experiences here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then,&lt;br /&gt;
NAREN&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>